A Finding Aid to the Robert Bruce Inverarity Papers, circa 1840s-1997, in the Archives of American Art AAA.inverobe
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1938-1990, undated; Series 4; (Boxes 3-6, OV 19-20; 2.5 linear ft.)
  - Photography (Box 5)
    - Rights and Reproductions (Birmingham Museum of Art), 1987-1988, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Sale and Exhibition Inquiries, 1984-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Preservation, 1955-1978, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Primitive Peoples, Costume and Ornament, undated (Box 6, Folder 2-7)
  - Travel, 1964-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Wenner-Gren Symposium, "The Use of Computers in Anthropology,", 1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Adirondack Museum Building Plans, 1957 and 1963 (Box OV 19)
  - Inverarity Collection, Printed Material (poster and broadside), 1976 (Box OV 20)
- Art Work, circa 1840s-1969, undated; Series 5; (Boxes 6, 12, 16, OV 21; 1.3 linear ft.)
  Most of Inverarity's sketchbooks are in published books that were converted to sketchbooks by replacing most of the text block with tipped in sheets of drawing paper. In addition to pencil and ink drawings, and a small number of watercolors they include notes scattered throughout. Vol. 1 contains sketches of places in Washington and California, and includes designs for woodcarving. Vol. 2 contains sketches of places in Washington, Oregon, Montana, and the Midwest. Vols. 3, 4 and 5 contain sketches of places in Washington. Vols. 6 and 7 contain sketches of Alaska. Vol. 8 contains sketches of unidentified subjects. Notes of particular interest are on camouflage (Vol. 6) and artists' materials and techniques (Vol. 8).
  Art work by other artists includes a gouache by Tobey, produced in his youth and said to be his first painting. Drawings include caricatures of Inverarity by Anfinson and unknown. Display panels for a small exhibit on Airbrush Stencil Prints produced by the WPA Federal Art Project include didactic text with photographs of the technique, sample stencils, prints at various stages of completion, and finished prints.
  In addition, there are drawings among Inverarity's writings and notes (Series 3), among notes in subject files (Series 4) and filed with some of the WPA printed material (Series 8).
  5.1: By Inverarity, 1928-1969, undated
  5.2: By Other Artists, circa 1840s-1964
  - By Inverarity, 1928-1969, undated; 5.1
    - Design for Boeing Brochures, circa 1946 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Drawings and Notes for Book Designs, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
    - Drawings and Sketches, 1929-circa 1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Sketchbooks (Box 6)
      - Volumes 1 and 2, 1928-1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Volumes 3, 5, and 6, 1941-1942, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Volumes 7 and 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - By Other Artists, circa 1840s-1964; 5.2
    - Drawings (pencil, ink, and charcoal), Anfinson - Warshaw and Unknown, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Anfinson, Friatson
      Bird, Reilly
      Lozkins (?)
      Polloen, A. L.
      Royer, Dorothy
      Warshaw, Howard
      Unknown
    - Paintings (Box 6)
      - Inverarity, Madeline (oil portrait of Miss Wallace-Dunlap by Inverarity's great-great grandmother; framed), undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Tobey, Mark (watercolor and gouache), undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Prints (Box 6)
      - Barnes, Ray and Unknown, 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Matulka, Jan (framed), undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Sketches (pencil) by Mark Tobey, circa 1935 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Airbrush Stencil Prints, WPA Federal Art Project Display, circa 1936-circa 1941 (Box 16)
    - Drawings of Inverarity House (interior and exterior), 1964 (Box OV 21)
- Scrapbooks, 1928-1991, undated; Series 6; (Boxes 7-8; 1.1 linear ft.)
  Inverarity compiled five scrapbooks. Volumes 1 through 3 consist mainly of newspaper clippings and miscellaneous printed items concerning his career as an artist and teacher, WPA administrator, and museum director. In addition, volume 1 includes a small number of photographs. Volume 4 preserves items designed by Inverarity - book covers, letterheads, greeting cards, brochures, etc. - and biographical information. Volume 5, devoted to Inverarity's monograph Art of the Northwest Coast Indians (University of California Press, 1950), includes a small amount of correspondence and a few photographs as well as reviews and advertisements.
  - Vol. 1, 1928-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 2, 1936-1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 3, 1956-1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 4: Designs by Inverarity and Biographical Information, 1943-1979, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 5: Art of the Northwest Coast Indians, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Sound Recordings, 1980-1990; Series 7; (Box 8; 3 folders)
  - Robert Bruce Inverarity, interviewed by Craig Gilborn, September 18-19, 1990; (5 audiocassettes) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Ernie and Helen Johnson conversing with Robert Bruce and Jane Inverarity (about Inverarity's departure from the Museum of International Folk Art), September 30, 1980; (1 audiocassette with transcript) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Grace T. Stevenson conversing with Robert Bruce and Jane Inverarity (includes references to Mark Tobey and Morris Graves), March 1981; (1 audiocassette) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, 1902-1995, undated; Series 8; (Boxes 8-11, 13, OV 22; 3.4 linear ft.)
  WPA items relate to the Federal Art Project and consist of published administrative reports and clippings about the project, and printed items produced by the Federal Art Project.
  Printed material by Inverarity includes articles on a wide variety of topics, his book Art of the Northwest Coast Indians (1950), and two published portfolios, 12 Photographs by R. B. Inverarity, F.R.S.A. (1940) and Moveable Masks and Figures of the North Pacific Coast Indians (1941). Among the printed material by other authors are articles, books, reports, and other items about or mentioning Inverarity, and books designed or illustrated by Inverarity.
  Miscellaneous items include a catalog of the Cornish School - where Inverarity met Mark Tobey and later taught - and catalogs and brochures of Freemont College/University and the University of Scientific Method where he studied. Also of interest are a few ephemeral items designed by Inverarity for the Adirondack Museum and others.
  Additional printed material can be found as attachments to correspondence (Series 2), with subject files (Series 4), and in scrapbooks (Series 6).
  This series is organized into 4 subseries:
  8.1: WPA, circa 1936-circa 1941, undated
  8.2: By Inverarity, 1930-1976, undated
  8.3: By Other Authors, 1902-1995, undated
  8.4: Miscellaneous Items, 1931-1988, undated
  - WPA, circa 1936-circa 1941, undated; 8.1
    - Federal Art Project (Box 8)
      - Booklets, 1940-1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - General Reports and Directives, circa 1936-1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
      - Clippings, 1938-1941 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Designs (drawings and printed items), 1936, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Exhibition Notices, 1936-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Federal Sponsored Community Art Centers, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Federal Art Project, Material by State (Box 8)
      - California, 1937-1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Illinois, 1938-1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Iowa, 1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - New York, 1937-1941 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Oregon, 1937-1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Utah, 1938-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Washington, 1938-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
    - Federal Works Agency Technical Series, Art Circulars Nos. 4 and 5, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - By Inverarity, 1930-1976, undated; 8.2
    - Articles, Books, Brochures, Pamphlets, etc., 1930-1950 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    - Articles, Books, Brochures, Pamphlets, etc., 1950-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
    - Moveable Masks and Figures of the North Pacific Coast Indians, 1941 (Box 13 (sol))
    - 12 Photographs by R. B. Inverarity, F.R.S.A., 1940 (Box 13 (sol))
    - Maps, 1943-1945 (Box OV 22)
      - "Navy War Map No. 1: The Mediterranean" (Box OV 22)
      - "Navy War Map No. 2: South China Sea Area" (Box OV 22)
      - "Navy War Map No. 3: North Sea Area" (Box OV 22)
  - By Other Authors, 1902-1995, undated; 8.3
    - About or Mentioning Inverarity, 1930-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8-17)
    - About or Mentioning Inverarity, 1987-1995, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Books Designed or Illustrated by Inverarity, 1958-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3-7)
      Azarpay, Guitty. Urartian Art and Archaeology: A Chronological Study
      Blum, Shirley Neilsen. Early Netherlandish Triptychs: A Study in Patronage
      Clark, Ella E. Indian Legends of the Pacific Northwest (illustrated by Inverarity)
      Geiringer, Karl. Hayden: A Creative Life in Music
      Robinson, Geroid Tanquary. Rural Russia Under the Old Regime
      Sauer, Carl O. Northern Mists (jacket drawing by Inverarity)
      The School of American Research and the Museum of New Mexico. Morleyana: A Collection of Writings in Memorium, Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1883- 1948
    - Book Inscribed to Duncan G. Inverarity (father of Robert Bruce), 1911 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Books Inscribed to Robert Bruce Inverarity (by Max Ernst, Hilaire Hiler, Sally Kent, and Man Ray), 1934-1964 (Box 10, Folder 9-11)
    - Brochures for Boeing Designed and Illustrated by Inverarity, circa 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Clippings (Box 10)
      - About Artists (A-Z by artist), 1949-1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - About or Mentioning Inverarity, 1929-1957, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1932-1992, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Designed by Inverarity (Box 11)
        - Adirondack Museum Ephemera, 1950s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous Items, 1945, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Harriman Alaska Expedition, Vols. I and II (Duncan G. Inverarity [father] was a professional photographer who accompanied the expedition), 1902 (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
    - Color Harmony Manual (Container Corporation of America), 1948 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1931-1988, undated; 8.4
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations (A-Z by artist), 1942-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Programs, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Reproductions (Napoleonic battle scene; jester), undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - School Catalogs and Brochures (Cornish School, Freemont College/University, and University of Scientific Method), 1931-circa 1948 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Photographs, circa 1870s-1990, undated; Series 9; (Boxes 11, 14-17, OV 23; 3.0 linear ft.)
  Photographs of art work are arranged by artist. Many photographs of Inverarity's work are views of framed items hanging in his home. Other views show large numbers of framed items gathered into one room (on chair seats and propped up against furniture) in order to record the maximum number of items in one picture; in many cases, these are portraits of artists photographed by Inverarity. Photographs of people consist of artists (including original and copy prints of portraits by Inverarity), friends, colleagues, and various groups.
  Photographs of places include museums where Inverarity was Director (Museum of International Folk Art and the Adirondack Museum ), places where he lived (Ridgefield, Conn. and La Jolla, Calif.), and travel pictures (Amsterdam, Burma, Egypt, Greece, Italy, Nepal, Scandinavia, and Thailand). Of particular interest are a large number of photographs taken on his 1932 trip to British Columbia to study the Haida Indians. In addition, there are several nineteenth century photographs of family homes and various locations in South America, probably taken by his father.
  Most of the WPA photographs document work of the Federal Art Project in Washington State. Multiple photographs mounted on many large cardboard panels (probably for display) show individual works of art, exhibition installations, and views of various art centers, etc. Other photographs are of individual works of art and include some Index of American Design drawings, mosaic procedures, and the mosaic for the Municipal Auditorium in Long Beach, California. Among the miscellaneous subjects are a view of the microreader invented by Inverarity, and his art photographs - boats, figure studies, industrial scenes, and landscapes.
  Photographs known to have been taken by Inverarity are clearly identified. Prints, slides, and color transparencies are interfiled. In addition, a small number of photographs are attached to Series 1: Correspondence, in many subject files (Series 4), and in Series 6: Scrapbooks. Of particular note is Man Ray's photograph of his studio, sent as a greeting card (Christmas?) in 1952 and filed with correspondence.
  This series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  9.1: Art Work, circa 1950-circa 1970s, undated
  9.2: People, 1920s-1979, undated
  9.3: Places, circa 1870s-1990, undated
  9.4: WPA, circa 1936-circa 1941
  9.5: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1957-1981, undated
  - Art Work, circa 1950-circa 1970s; 9.1
    - Ernst, Max (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Graves, Morris (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Illustrations for Art of the Northwest Coast Indians by Robert Bruce Inverarity, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Inverarity, Madeline (portrait of Miss Wallace-Dunlop by Inverarity's great-great grandmother; photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce, Paintings for U.S. Navy (color transparencies), undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce, Portraits of Artists (framed photographs) displayed in his home; photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Inverarity [Robert Bruce and Jane] Collection of Northwest Coast Indian Art, Museum of Mankind, London, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - Tobey, Mark (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified Artists (photographs by Inverarity), 1989, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified Artists, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - People, 1920s-1979, undated; 9.2
    - Artists (contact sheets with multiple portraits; photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Ball, Eliot Porter (photographs by Inverarity), circa 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Byner, Winter and Ashley Montague (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Derbyshire, Dr. (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Deutsch, Hilda [Mrs. Carl Morris] (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Duchamp, Marcel (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Ernst, Max (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Ernst, Max and Dorothea Tanning (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Feitelson, Lorser (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Fitzsimmons, James (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Frugé, August (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Graves, Morris (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Groups of Artists (photographs by Inverarity), 1949 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Groups, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Guldbeck, Lori and Per, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Haley, John (photographs by Inverarity), 1950 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Hiler, Hilaire (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Inverarity, Jane (photographs by Inverarity), 1956-1976, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Inverarity, Jane with Others (photographs by Inverarity), 1976, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Inverarity, Jane and Robert Bruce, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce, 1952-circa 1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce with Others, 1920s-1958, undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Kent, Rockwell (photographs by Inverarity), 1963, undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - LeBrun, Rico (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Lefebvre, René (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Lovacrubias, Miguel, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Lundeberg, Helen (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - MacDonald-Wright, Stanton (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Morris, Carl (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Perit, Suzy (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Ray, Julie Man (photographs by Inverarity), 1948 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Ray, Man (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Reagh, Bill (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Royer, Dorothy (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Stazack, Carol (photographs by Inverarity), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Tanning, Dorothea (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Tobey, Mark (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Tobey, Mark, undated (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Val Clear and Kenneth Downer (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Warshaw, Howard (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Wassar, Art and Ellie (photographs by Inverarity), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Whitman, Walt (possibly by Matthew Brady; contemporary copy), undated (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Wunderlich, Rudi (photographs by Inverarity), 1957 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Unidentified ("A.E." [daughter?] and unknown woman; photographs by Inverarity), 1976, undated (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Deutsch, Hilda [Mrs. Carl Morris] (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Duchamp, Marcel (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Ernst, Max (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Ernst, Max and Dorothea Tanning (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Feitelson, Lorser (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Fitzsimmons, James (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Graves, Morris (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Graves, Morris and Malcolm Roberts (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Haley, John (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Hiler, Hilaire (photographs by Interarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Inverarity, Jane (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce (self portrait), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Inverarity, Robert Bruce (photograph by Douglas C. Sly), 1947 (Box 14 (sol))
    - Knowles, Joe (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Le Brun, Rico (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Lundeberg, Helen (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Mac Donald-Wright, Stanton (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Morris, Carl (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Perit, Suzy (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Petric, Mrs. Ludin (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Ray, Julie Man (photographs by Inveraritiy), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Ray, Man (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Royer, Dorothy (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Swan, Charles (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Tanning, Dorothea (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Tobey, Mark (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Val Clear, Charles and Kenneth Downing (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Warshaw, Howard (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
    - Wessels, Glenn (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 14 (sol))
  - Places, circa 1870s-1990, undated; 9.3
    - Adirondack Museum, 1957, 1971, undated (Box 11, Folder 64-65)
    - Adirondack Museum (photograph album, vol. 1), undated (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Amsterdam (photographs by Inverarity), 1962 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - British Columbia (trip to study Haida Indians; photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 68-69)
    - Dikill, Peganum, Istanbul (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Family Homes, circa 1870s-1880s (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Greece and Egypt (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Italy, circa 1870s-1880s (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - La Jolla, Calif. (photographs by Inverarity), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Mt. St. Helens, Calif. (photographs by Inverarity), 1990 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Museum of International Folk Art, 1953, undated (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Ridgefield, Conn. (photographs by Inverarity), circa 1957-1958, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - Rome; New York City Hotel and Airport (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - St. Paul's Church, circa 1880s (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Samish Island, Wash. (photographs by Inverarity), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - South America, 1870s (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Unidentified (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Adirondack Museum (photograph album, vol. 2), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Burma; Nepal; Scandinavia; Thailand; Unidentified (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Family Houses, circa 1880s (Box 15 (sol))
  - WPA, circa 1936-circa 1941; 9.4
    - Mosaic Procedures, circa 1936-circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 83-84)
    - Washington State WPA Federal Art Project, circa 1936-circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Washington State WPA Federal Art Project black and white negatives, circa 1936-circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Municipal Auditorium Mosaic, Long Beach, Calif., 1938 (Box OV 23)
    - Washington State WPA Federal Art Project, circa 1936-circa 1941 (Box 16-17)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1957-1981, undated; 9.5
    - Box Collection (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Broadside, "Monumental Grandeur of the Mississippi Valley..." (photograph by Inverarity), undated (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - "Gold Thread Pillow Case taken by my grandfather when 92 Highlanders raided Queen's Palace, New Delhi" (35-mm color slides by Inverarity), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Microreader Invented by Inverarity, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Boats (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Figure Studies (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Industrial Subjects (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Landscapes (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 15 (sol))
    - Pacific Northwest Culture (photographs by Inverarity), undated (Box 15 (sol))